# **SRIRAM GOPALAN**

• Home: 408 775 4062 • sriramgopalan58@gmail.com

# **Professional Summary**

Confident and experienced Solutions Architect with more than 7 years of comprehensive experience designing, developing, testing and deploying innovation solutions for clients across different sectors. Knowledgeable about a wide range of software programming languages and deployment tools. Excellent at juggling multiple tasks and working under pressure. Good at collaborating with Sales, Marketing and Product teams to develop a successful product.

# **Work History**

#### Solution Architect, 01/2016 to Current

#### Inspyrus Inc - San Carlos, California

I was responsible for the implementation and success of Inspyrus's very first customer on Inspyrus cloud. I was also responsible for leading the implementation of many high profile clients like SalesForce, Amway, Verifone, Amazon, Wonderful Company.

Listed below are my responsibilities:

- Technical lead responsible for the success of customer delivery engagements on the Inspyrus Cloud or On-Premise
- Lead the analysis process in understanding customer challenges and requirements
- Design, document and develop exceptional solutions with Inspyrus that fulfill customer requirements in the expected timeframes
- Develop custom solutions as needed to fulfill requirements not available directly in the Inspyrus product
- Present Inspyrus product and solution capabilities in a clear and understandable manner to customers and partners, including executives
- Develop proof of concepts and demos to prove that Inspyrus understands and can address customer and partner requirements
- Continually act as a liaison with Inspyrus Technical Support, Engineering, Marketing, and Sales teams to provide input from customers, as well as be educated on new advancements in products
- Proactively identify and implement ways to increase efficiency in Solutions Architecture processes; assess results and refine
- Mentor new team members and product consultants

## Senior Product Consultant, 01/2014 to 12/2015

## Inspyrus Inc – San Carlos, California

Having joined as the fourth employee of Inspyrus team my duties were far more than my role entails. Some of them were:

- · Worked with Product Development team in debugging and fixing issues in the core product
- Delivering pre-sales demo to prospects and addressing questions from sales team
- Instrumental in the go-live of first Cloud Customer
- Gathered and documented functional requirements from customers
- Installed Inspyrus Software for On-Premise customers
- Configured Inspyrus's software based on customer requirements, For eg: workflows, reports, data migration
- Deliver end user training and fix issues during Integration and User Acceptance Testing
- · Played the role of support manager, triaging production issues post go live

#### **Product Consultant**, 05/2013 to 12/2013

Esker Inc - Madison, wisconsin

- Mentor Associate Consultants in Implementations to customize Esker products such as end-user interface, reports and workflow based on gathered requirements
- · Assisted Sales Engineers in presales to help clients understand Esker's product
- Troubleshoot issues that came up in the course of configuring software and worked with sales, research & development and technical support teams to resolve these issues
- Trained end users on the product via web based demos, face to face meetings

### Associate Product Consultant, 06/2011 to 04/2013

Esker Inc - Madison, Wisconsin

- Gathered and documented functional requirements from customers
- Customized the Esker products such as end-user interface, reports and workflow based on gathered requirements for both On-Premise customers and Cloud customers
- Troubleshoot issues that came up in the course of configuring software and worked with sales, research & development and technical support teams to resolve these issues

### **Skills**

- Service Oriented Architecture
- Enterprise Applications/Technologies
- Web Services Integrations (Soap, Rest)
- SDLC Principles
- Requirements Gathering And Analysis
- · Workflow analysis
- Order to cash, Procure to Pay Processes

- Languages: Javascript, HTML5, Java, PL/SQL.
  Oracle BPEL, Oracle BPM, XML, LDAP
- Databases: Oracle database (11g,12c), Microsoft sql server, IBM DB2
- ERP Systems: Oracle EBS (11i, r12), JDE (E1 9.1, 9.2), PSFT (9.1,9.2), SAP, Asset-works, TCIMS, Maximo
- Protocols: LDAP, SSL, TLS, IMAP, IMAPS, SAML, SMTP
- Technology: Oracle Weblogic And Fusion Middleware Servers (SOA, IPM, OSB, Oracle Content Server), Documentum
- Source Code Systems: bitbucket, git-hub
- Deployment Tools: ant, Jenkins
- · OS: Windows, Linux, Mac
- Other: Qlikview, Oracle Webcenter Capture, Oracle Forms Recognition

### **Education**

Master of Science: Operations Research, Industrial Engineering, 2011

University of Wisconsin - Madison - Madison, WI

Bachelor of Science: Instrumentation Control Engineering, 2009

National Institute of Technology, Tiruchirappalli - TamillNadu, India